He was growing into middle age...
他正值壮年…
...and was living then in a bungalow on Woodland Avenue.
…住在森林大道的一座平房里
He installed himself in a rocking chair...
他坐在摇椅里…
...and smoked a cigar down in the evenings...
…在暮色里抽着雪茄…
...as his wife wiped her pink hands on an apron...
…他的妻子在围裙上擦着粉红的双手…
...and reported happily on their two children.
…和他们的两个孩子说着什么
His children knew his legs...
孩子们熟悉父亲的双腿…
...the sting of his mustache against their cheeks.
…还有他的胡子扎在自己脸上的感觉
They didn't know how their father made his living or why they so often moved.
但他们不知道父亲如何谋生 也不知道为什么经常要搬家
They didn't even know their father's name.
他们甚至不知道父亲的名字
He was listed in the city directory as Thomas Howard.
在市政府的名录上 他叫做托马斯・霍华德
And he went everywhere unrecognized...
走在街上没人认得他…
...and lunched with Kansas City shopkeepers and merchants...
…他时常与堪萨斯城的店主和商人 一起吃午饭…
...calling himself a cattleman or a commodities investor...
…自称是牧人或者投资商人…
...someone rich and leisured who had the common touch.
…一个平易近人，有钱而又悠闲的人
He had two incompletely healed bullet holes in his chest...
他的胸口有两处未能痊愈的弹痕…
...and another in his thigh.
…大腿上也有一处
He was missing the nub of his left middle finger...
他左手中指少了两节…
...and was cautious, lest that mutilation be seen.
…对此他很是小心，唯恐被人看见
He also had a condition that was referred to as "granulated eyelids"...
他还有一种称为“粒状眼睑”的症状…
...and it caused him to blink more than usual...
…这使得他比常人更频繁的眨眼…
...as if he found creation slightly more than he could accept.
…好像在他看来 周围的人们让他有点难以接受
Rooms seemed hotter when he was in them.
他在的时候，房间似乎更加炎热
Rains fell straighter.
雨似乎下得更频繁
Clocks slowed.
时间似乎过得更慢
Sounds were amplified.
声音被放得更大
He considered himself a Southern loyalist and guerrilla...
他认为自己是一个 在一场永无终结的内战中…
...in a Civil War that never ended.
…忠于南方的游击队员
He regretted neither his robberies, nor the 17 murders that he laid claim to.
对于他做过的抢劫案，以及被控诉的17起谋杀案 他毫不悔过
He had seen another summer under in Kansas City, Missouri...
在密苏里州的堪萨斯城 他又迎来了一个新的夏天
...and on September 5th in the year 1881...
…1881年9月5日…
...he was 34 years old.
…他34岁
You just... You just slide them things right in there, right in your sleeve...
你只要…你只要把东西滑进这里 就这里，到你袖子里…
...and then, when you get ready, you just shake it out.
…然后等准备好了，就甩出来
Like that, right there. You shake it out.
像那样，看，甩出来
Mary Todd Lincoln, tyrant's wife, fall into hysterics when the moon was full.
玛丽・托德・林肯，暴君的妻子 在月圆时发疯了
President's men would tie her up with hay-baling wire...
总统的手下会用干草绳把她捆起来…
...keep her from ripping her husband's ears off.
…以免她丈夫的耳朵被她咬掉
You never heard word one about the wife of the Confederacy's Jefferson Davis, did you?
你从没听别人说过 杰弗逊・戴维斯的老婆的闲话吧？ （美国内战中南方联邦的总统）
- I didn't. - No, you didn't.
- 没有 - 对，没有
He did his duty by her.
她可是她丈夫的贤内助
- Oh, my God, I'm speaking to children. - No, I get it, I get it, I get it.
- 噢，天，忘了你是小孩子了 - 不，我听懂了，我听懂了
The president of the Confederacy discerned his wife's needs and satisfied them...
联邦总统明白妻子的需要 他用高超的技巧和礼节…
...with the utmost skill and the utmost courtesy.
…满足了她
- Charley, you spit all over my boot. - Sorry. Sorry, sorry, Jesse.
- 查理，你喷得我满鞋子都是 - 对不起，对不起，杰西
- Here, get it off. - I'll wipe it... I'll wipe it off.
- 这里，弄干净 - 我来擦…我会擦干净的
But Abraham Lincoln probably sent his wife on a shopping expedition.
但亚伯拉罕・林肯也许让他老婆 去疯狂购物了
- A three-act play. - With money stole from us.
- 一场三幕的戏 - 花的是从我们这偷去的钱
Chow!
开饭！
I think insanity run on both sides of that Lincoln family.
我看林肯家双方都有病
You're right about that.
你说的没错
The river... You jump in the river.
那河…你跳进去
- Chow! - Don't be shy now, Dick.
- 开饭！ - 别害羞，迪克
- One more piece of meat. - When you diddle a lot...
- 再来一块肉 - 你骗人多了以后…
There's a good piece of bacon fat in there for him.
给他留了一块很好的培根肥肉
Excuse me.
打扰了
I see I've traipsed right on in and interrupted you.
我随便散步，没想到打扰你了
Who are you, then?
那么你是谁？
Bob Ford.
鲍勃・福特
Charley's brother?
查理的弟弟？
Yeah.
对
I was lying when I said I just happened down here.
我刚才说谎了，我不是偶尔路过
I've been looking for you. I feel lousy I didn't say so at the outset.
我在找你 我一开始没说实话，是不是很让人讨厌
Folks take me for a nincompoop...
因为我给人的第一印象常常很不好…
...on account of the shabby first impression I make, whereas I think of myself...
…别人都当我是傻子 但我觉得自己…
...as being just a rung down from the James brothers.
…只比詹姆斯兄弟差一点
I was hoping if I ran into you aside from those peckerwoods...
我希望如果我避开那些啄木鸟来见你…
...I could show you how special I am.
…我就能向你展示我的特别之处
I honestly believe I'm destined for great things, Mr. James.
我坚信我注定要干一番大事业的，詹姆斯先生
I got qualities that don't come shining through right at the outset.
我的特别之处一开始并不引人注目
You give me a chance, I'll get the job done. I guarantee you that.
给我一个机会，我能把活干好 我向你保证
Hey, Dick, is it true you diddled a squaw?
嗨，迪克，听说你骗了个印第安女人？
Come on, you can tell me. I've always wanted to lay down with a redskin.
快点，告诉我 我一直想睡一个红皮肤女人 （红皮肤：对印第安人的侮辱称呼）
Well, Charley...
这个，查理…
...there's a feeling that comes over you...
…你会有这样一种感觉…
...getting inside a woman whose hands has scalped a congregation.
…这个女人的手割下了一个教士的头皮 而你进入了她的身体…
There's this thunderous sound that comes from their cooch...
她们的阴道里有雷鸣般的声音…
...on account of the fact that they birth a child standing upright...
…因为她们站着生孩子…
...like a wild animal. - What's it sound like?
- …像野兽那样 - 什么样的声音？
Whatever a thunderous cooch sounds like there, Charley. I don't know.
雷鸣般的阴道是啥样就是啥样，查理 我不知道
No.
不对
They got a noisy quim on account of the fact that...
她们的阴道很吵，是因为…
...they use their cunnis as a saddlebag to carry sundries across the plains.
…她们在平原上穿行的时候用它来装杂货
Come on, what'd it really feel like? Did it feel good?
少来了，到底什么感觉？爽吗？
Come on, fess up, now.
快点坦白，快
I like you, Charley.
我喜欢你，查理
I like you too, Charley.
我也喜欢你，查理
Well...
这个…
You're not so special, Mr. Ford.
你并不特别，福特先生
You're just like any other tyro who's prinked himself up for an escapade.
你就像其他那些新手一样 自我吹嘘，想得到一显身手的机会
Hoping to be a gunslinger like them nickel books are about.
希望成为那些江湖小说里面的神枪手
You may as well quench your mind of it...
你可以歇歇了…
...because you don't have the ingredients, son.
…因为你不是那块料，孩子
Well, I'm sorry to hear you feel that way...
很遗憾，我的话影响了你的判断…
...as I put such stock in your opinions.
…让你这么看我
As for me being a gunslinger, I've just got this one granddaddy Paterson Colt...
作为一个枪手 我只有一把古董级的左轮手枪…
...and a borrowed belt to stick it in.
…还借了一条皮带来固定它
But I also got an appetite for greater things.
但我也的确有雄心壮志
I hoped by joining up with you, it'd put me that much closer to getting them.
我希望借着加入你们的机会 能让自己离目标更近一步
Well, what am I supposed to say to that?
哎，让我怎么说好呢？
Let me be your sidekick tonight.
今晚我当你的拍档
Sidekick?
拍档？
So you can examine my grit and intelligence.
这样你能看到我的不足和闪光点
I don't know what it is about you...
我不知道你这人到底怎样…
...but the more you talk, the more you give me the willies.
…但你说的越多，就越让我感到不安
Now, I don't believe I want you anywhere within earshot this evening, okay?
我想我今晚不想看到你，好吗？
You understand?
明白吗？
- Well, I'm sorry... - Why don't you just get now? Scat.
- 我很遗憾… - 你怎么还不走？快点
All right.
好吧
I was with a girl once, wasn't a squaw.
我曾经和一个女孩在一起，她不是印第安人
But she was pretty.
但她很漂亮
She had yellow hair like a...
她金黄的头发就像…
Oh, like something.
噢，就是像什么东西
Like hair bobbed from a ray of sunlight?
像一缕灿烂的阳光？
Yeah. Yeah, like that.
对，对，就像那样
Boy, you... You talk good.
哥们，你…你说话真好听
You can hide things in vocabulary.
华丽的词藻能表达感情
Maybe you and me could write her a note, send it by post?
也许你能帮我给她写个纸条，寄过去？
See, all you gotta do, Ed...
跟你说吧，艾德，你要做的…
...is predict her needs and beat her to the punch.
…就是琢磨她的心思，然后一举搞定
Well, this girl, she has a real specific job.
嗯，这个女孩，她的工作真的很特别
- Specific? - We was only together once.
- 特别？ - 我们只在一起过一次
She...
她…
She was afraid of lightning, and she came up under the wagon and...
她怕闪电，她从马车下面…
...just cuddled right up to me.
…向上抱住了我
She give me a kind price too.
她也给了我很优惠的价格
Well, I'll be. That is specific.
嗯，的确很特别
Yeah, sure, she'd been with other people...
嗯，当然，她也跟别人在一起过…
...but the kind of things she said to me...
…但她对我说的那些话…
...people just don't say unless they really mean it.
…显然是真情流露
My love said she would marry only me
我的爱人说她只会嫁给我
And Jove himself could not make her care.
即使朱庇特也不能让她动心 （朱庇特：罗马最高神）
For what women say to lovers, you'll agree
对于女人说给爱人的话，我想你也同意
One writes on running water or on air.
就像写在流水里，写在空气里
My God, that's good. Let's write her that.
老天，真不错，那我们就这么写给她
No.
不行
Poetry don't work on whores.
跟妓女说这些诗情画意的话没用
How do you do?
你好吗？
Am I too late to wish you a happy birthday?
现在祝你生日快乐是不是太迟了？
How'd you know?
你怎么知道我的生日？
You'd be surprised at what I got stored away.
你要是知道我对你的了解程度，会很惊讶
I'm an authority on the James boys.
我是詹姆斯小伙方面的权威
Is you?
是吗？
Well... Well, your brother Frank and I, we just had a real nice visit.
嗯…我刚刚和你哥哥弗兰克 友好的交谈了一会儿
Just chit-chatting about this and that, right over there.
就是随便聊聊，在那边
And must've been a hundred subjects entertained...
大概聊了一百个话题…
Good Lord, you know what this stew needs?
老天，你知道这炖汤应该配什么吗？
Dumplings?
饺子？
Noodles.
面条
You eat yourself some noodle stew and your clock'll tick all night.
来一碗炖汤面，你一晚上都会回味
You ever see that woman up in Fayette? Suck noodles up her nose.
你见过费耶德市的那个女人吗？ 她用鼻孔吸面条吃
- In Fayette? - I don't believe I have.
- 在费耶德？ - 我想我没见过
You never heard of her, huh?
你没听说过她，嗯？
You got canals up there you never dreamed of.
那里有你想象不到的好事
I don't like to harp on a subject...
有些话我不喜欢反复说…
I don't care who comes with me. Never have.
我不关心谁跟我一起做事，从不关心
That's why they call me gregarious.
所以大家都觉得我很合群
I hear you and young Stovepipe here had a real nice visit.
我听说你和这个戴礼帽的小伙子 谈得很不错
Your boys have got about a acre of lumber to haul, dingus.
你们还有一大片木头要砍呢，小子
You better goose them down yonder.
你最好赶紧赶他们干活去
The James Gang committed over 25 bank, train and stagecoach robberies...
1867年至1881年间 詹姆斯一伙犯下了超过25起…
...from 1867 to 1881.
…在银行、火车和公共马车上的抢劫案
But except for Frank and Jesse James...
但除了弗兰克・詹姆斯和杰西・詹姆斯…
...all the original members were now either dead or in prison.
…其余所有初期成员 现在不是已死就是已经入狱
- Mine eye All my soul and all my every part
我的眼睛、灵魂和我的身体
And for this sin, there is no remedy
这种罪恶，没有补救方法
It is so grounded inward in my heart.
它已经深入我的心底
So for their last robbery at Blue Cut...
所以在蓝切地的最后一次抢劫行动中…
...the brothers recruited a gang of petty thieves and country rubes...
…兄弟俩从附近的山林里招募了一些…
...culled from the local hillsides.
…小贼和乡下人
Right on schedule, Buck!
准点到达，动手！
Snuff those lanterns!
灭了那些灯笼！
Look at those fools. They're gonna trip and shoot each other into females.
看看那群傻子，他们肯定会互相绊倒 然后开枪把对方打成女人
I bet you I could find them husbands if they do.
我打赌，他们要是这么做 我可以给他们找几百个女人
Fan out!
散开！
Hold your fire!
别开枪！
- Watch him! - Going down.
- 注意他！ - 下去
Hold your fire, you idiots!
别开枪，你们这些白痴！
Hold your fire!
别开枪！
Let me in.
让我进去
Buck! Boys!
动手！小伙子们！
Buck, this way!
动手，这边！
Do you think that lock will hold?
你觉得这锁撑得住吗？
No, I don't.
不觉得
Let's go, let's go.
快走，快走
Let's not get clever, nor courageous, any of you.
你们别装聪明，也别逞强
Hey there, boys! These are all for me?
你好啊，小伙子！ 这些都是给我的？
Looks like Christmas morning in here.
看起来像是圣诞节的早晨
Hey, friend.
你好，朋友
You mind if I have a peek around?
我四处偷窥一下你不介意吧？
This shit. Nope.
垃圾，不行
Nope.
不行
You got anything good here?
你这里有什么好东西吗？
It could be.
也许有
Open that safe.
保险箱打开！
Do it!
快点！
- You didn't have to bop him. - Yeah, he did. They needed convincing.
- 你没必要砸他头啊 - 不，有必要，要不他们不服
They got their company rules, I got my mean streak...
他们有他们的规矩，我有我的办法…
...and that's how we get things done around here.
…这就是我们干活的方式
- Get on over here and attend to this thing. - Come on, go.
- 过来看着他 - 快点，过去
Hold your fire, you idiots!
别开枪，一群白痴！
Dig deeper.
再往里翻翻
- Come on! - Give me your money.
快点！给我钱
- And you, stand up. - Let's see your hands.
- 还有你，站起来 - 让我看看你的手
What have you got?
你有什么？
Speak English.
说英语
Money. Money. You understand that?
钱，钱，你听得懂吗？
Give me your money!
给我钱！
There's some receipts.
有一些收据
I got fives.
有一些五块的钞票
Jesse. Jesse.
杰西，杰西
Don't look good.
看起来没啥东西
There ain't no 100,000 dollars in here, Dick.
这里没有十万美金，迪克
Get down on your knees.
跪下
Why?
为什么？
Well, you ought to pray.
噢，你得开始祈祷了
I'm gonna kill you.
因为我要杀了你
Get at!
跪下！
You're gonna have to make me.
那你得强迫我了
All right.
好吧
Don't shoot him! No, don't shoot him.
别杀他！不要，别杀他
Don't tell me what I can and cannot do, Ed.
轮不到你指挥我，艾德
Round them up!
集合！
Chicago newspaper publishers made a great deal of the Blue Cut train robbery...
芝加哥报业在蓝切地的火车抢劫案上大做文章…
...alleging that in no state but Missouri...
…声称除了密苏里之外，没有一个州…
...would the James brothers be tolerated for 12 years.
…会纵容詹姆斯兄弟达12年之久
Hey.
嗨
Can you keep a secret?
你嘴巴紧吗？
It depends on what you're concealing.
那要看你告诉我什么了
You afraid of the dark?
你害怕黑暗吗？
No.
不
You superstitious?
你迷信吗？
I put... I put an acorn in the window to keep the lightning out.
我放了…我放了一颗橡子在窗户上 来躲避闪电
Kid, you must've crept up on cat's paws.
孩子，你走路跟猫一样没声音
I'll wager that's the first and last time you'll ever be caught off-guard.
我打赌，这是你第一次，也是最后一次 被人突袭的机会
How old are you?
你几岁了？
Twenty.
二十
Except, well, I guess I won't really be 20 till...
不过，我想，要到一月份…
Till January, so...
我才20岁，所以…
I'm 19.
我19岁
Yeah, you feel older than that, though, don't you?
嗯，不过你是不是觉得自己 比实际年龄要老？
Yeah, I do.
是的，会觉得
Hey, Frank, you... You think the sheriff's out already?
嗨，弗兰克，你…你看 警方会不会已经出动了？
- More than likely. - Yeah.
- 相当有可能 - 是啊
I had a real fine time tonight.
今晚很顺利
- You think so? - Yup. Yeah.
- 是吗？ - 嗯，是的
Hey, I wasn't just flapping my lips about my kid brother and me.
嗨，我不只是在吹嘘我和我弟弟
What I figured was if you and Jesse could gauge our courage and our daring...
我想说的是，如果你和杰西 能看清我们的胆识和勇气…
...you might just make us your regular sidekicks.
…你就该把我们收做固定搭档
Your courage and your daring.
你们的勇气和胆识
I about heard all I want to about sidekicks. You sound like your damn brother.
关于搭档我听得够多了 你这口气跟你那该死的弟弟一样
Yeah. Well, I'll be square with you, it's Bob who put me up to it. He's...
哦，跟你直说吧 是我弟弟让我来跟你说这些的，他…
He's got plans for the James boys I can't even get the hang of.
他有本事加入詹姆斯兄弟的队伍 但我却完全做不好
- They're that complicated. - Yeah?
- 这活太复杂了 - 是吗？
Well, you can just get shed of that idea.
嗯，你们可以打消这个念头了
Because after tonight, there'll be no more shenanigans.
因为今晚之后，我们就要金盆洗手了
You can jot that down in your little diary.
你可以在日记上记下来
September 7th, 1881, the James Gang robbed one last train at Blue Cut...
1881年9月7日，詹姆斯一伙 在蓝切地抢劫了最后一辆火车…
...and gave up their nightriding for good.
…从此弃恶从善
Wait.
等等
Well, how are you gonna make your living?
那么，你以后准备靠什么吃饭？
Maybe I'll sell shoes.
也许我会去卖鞋
I can't believe I woke up this morning...
真不敢想象，早上起来…
...wondering if my daddy would loan me his overcoat...
…我还在想父亲是否会借我大衣穿…
...and here it is just past midnight...
…而现在才过午夜…
...l've already robbed a railroad train and I'm sitting in a rocking chair...
…我已经抢了一列火车，坐在摇椅上…
...chatting with none other than Jesse James.
…和独一无二的杰西・詹姆斯聊天了
Yeah, it's a wonderful world.
是啊，世界真奇妙
What's this?
这是什么？
Oh, yeah.
哦，对了
I was real agitated this morning, so I was wondering if I would know you or Frank...
今天早上我真的很激动 我在想是否能认出你或者弗兰克…
...tell you all apart, and so I had this clipping that described you both.
…分清楚你俩谁是谁 所以我带了这块描述你们的剪报
Want me to read it?
想听听吗？
Go on.
念吧
Well... I gotta find it. Hold on.
嗯…我找一下，等等
Here. Here.
在这里，找到了
"Jesse James, the youngest, has a face as smooth and innocent as a schoolgirl.
“杰西・詹姆斯，家里最小的孩子 一张脸像小姑娘一样，光滑又无辜
The blue eyes, very clear and penetrating, are never at rest.
蓝色的眼睛清澈而又明锐 而且总是十分警觉
His form is tall and graceful and capable of great endurance...
他外表高大，举止得体，善于忍耐…
...and great effort.
…和进取
Jesse is lighthearted, reckless, and devil-may-care.
杰西快乐而鲁莽，随遇而安
- There's always a smile on his lips..." - All right, all right, all right.
- 他嘴上总是挂着一丝微笑…” - 够了，够了，够了
Well, yeah, then it just... Frank, Frank, Frank. That's nothing. And then...
嗯，然后是…弗兰克，弗兰克，弗兰克 然后没了，然后…
You know what I got right next to my bed?
你知道我床边放着什么吗？
Is The Train Robbers, or, A Story of the James Boys by R.W. Stevens.
是《火车劫匪》，或者是R・W・史蒂文斯写的 《詹姆斯家小伙子的故事》
I mean, many's the night I stayed up...
我是说，多少个夜里 在空无一人的图书馆…
...with my eyes open and my mouth open...
…我两眼通红，张着嘴巴…
...just reading about your escapades in the Wide Awake Library.
…读着你们的故事
They're all lies, you know.
那些都是扯蛋，你应该知道
Yeah, of course they are.
是，当然是
You don't have to keep smoking that if it's making you bungey.
如果觉得难受就没必要一直抽烟
Alexander Franklin James would be in Baltimore...
亚历山大・富兰克林・詹姆斯 听说杰西・詹姆斯被暗杀的时候…
He had spurned his younger brother for being peculiar and temperamental.
因为他觉得弟弟性情古怪，喜怒无常 所以离开了他
But once he perceived that he would never see Jesse again...
但如果感觉到自己再也不会见到杰西…
...Frank would be wrought-up, perplexed, despondent.
…弗兰克应该会感到 着急，丧气，不知所措
My brother and me are hardly on speaking terms these days.
我哥哥已经不和我谈那档子事了
Well, I wasn't gonna mention it.
嗯，我也没打算说
Are you scared?
你怕了吗？
No, I'm just surprised a little.
没有，只是有点惊讶
They ain't as succulent as I like, the devil to clean...
它的肉不是我喜欢的那种多汁的
...but if a man skins them and fries them in garlic and oil...
…但如果剥了皮，用大蒜和油来烤…
...mercy, them's good eating.
…老天，那是相当好吃
Well, I never been that hungry.
这个，我还没饿到那个地步
I give them names.
我给它们取了名字
Such as?
比如说？
Such as enemies.
比如敌人
I give them names of enemies.
我给它们取了敌人的名字
Go tell Wood and Charley to get their gatherings together.
告诉伍德和查理准备好行李
All right.
好的
Me too?
我也是吗？
You can stay.
你可以留下
All right.
好吧
Hey.
嗨
- What do you want, peckerwood? - Nothing.
- 你想要什么，啄木鸟？ - 没什么
Except to say Jesse wants you two to gather your parts...
只是杰西让我叫你俩收拾好东西…
...get on your horses and get out of town.
…然后上马离开镇子
And me to stick around.
而我留下来
Well, whoa, I'm his cousin...
喔，我可是他的表弟…
...l'll have you know.
…我告诉你
My mama's his daddy's sister.
我妈妈是他爸爸的妹妹
Is that how they described it to you, Wood?
他们就是这么告诉你的，伍德？
You better watch your tongue, young sapling.
你说话最好注意点，小样
Why is it me who's gotta rattle his hocks out of town and not you, Bunny?
凭什么就该是我出去而不是你，小兔崽子？
Put your horns away. If I know Jess...
别激动，要我说…
...there's some real nasty sad-suzie work's gotta be done...
…一定是有一些又脏又累的活…
...and Bob's the ninny that has to do it.
…等着鲍勃这个呆子去干
Oh, yeah, I'm sure that's it, Charley.
哦，是啊，肯定是这样，查理
You only met him 12 hours ago. He doesn't even know your name.
你12个小时前才认识他 他甚至连你的名字都不知道
Wood! You tell your daddy I'll be in Kentucky in October.
伍德！告诉你爸 我十月份会在肯塔基州
We can hunt some birds together.
我们可以一起去打鸟
All right.
好吧
So how come it's Bob who gets to stay?
那为什么是鲍勃留下来了？
Bob's gonna move my gear to a house down the street.
鲍勃要把我的马具搬到 这条街前面的一座房子里去
See?
看到没？
- I don't mind. - Yeah, well.
- 我无所谓 - 嗯，好吧
Sounds like an adventure.
听起来像是冒险行动
They moved to 1017 Troost Avenue at night...
他们在夜间搬到了杜鲁斯特大道1017号…
...so that the neighborhood couldn't get a good look at them or their belongings.
…这样他们的邻居就不能看清他们 或是他们带来的东西
Then Bob thought Jesse would give him eight hours' sleep...
之后鲍勃以为杰西会让他睡八个小时…
...and a daydreaming goodbye.
…然后一大早让他走
But with a second day in the Thomas Howard house...
但在托马斯・霍华德的房子里 住了两天之后…
...Bob thought he might never go...
…鲍勃觉得也许他永远都不会离开了…
...but might be brought in as a good-natured cousin to the boy...
…也许他会成为小男孩的好脾气表哥…
...and a gentleman helper to Zee.
…还有芝的好帮手
He went everywhere with Jesse.
杰西到哪里他都跟着
They made trips to the Topeka Exchange Saloon...
他们去了托皮卡交易所酒吧…
...where Jesse could spend nearly 60 minutes sipping one glass of beer...
…在那里杰西会花上60分钟 细品一杯啤酒…
...and still complain about feeling tipsy.
…并仍然抱怨感到醉意
Bob would rarely vouchsafe his opinions as they talked.
交谈时，鲍勃几乎不发表自己的看法
If spoken to, he would fidget and grin.
如果被问到，他通常会不安和微笑
If Jesse palavered with another person, Bob secretaried their dialogue...
如果杰西在和别人商谈 鲍勃会在一旁仔细观察他们的对话…
...getting each inflection, reading every gesture and tic...
…注意他声调的变化，每个手势 以及面部肌肉的抽搐…
...as if he wanted to compose a biography of the outlaw...
…好像是在为一个逃犯撰写传记…
...or as if he were preparing an impersonation.
…又好像只在为模仿他做准备
Go away.
走开
Used to be couldn't no one sneak up on Jesse James.
过去没人能悄悄靠近杰西・詹姆斯
Now you think otherwise?
你觉得现在呢？
I ain't never seen you without your guns, neither.
我也从没见过你不带枪
I can't figure it out.
我想不通
Do you wanna be like me...
你是想变得像我…
...or do you wanna be me?
…还是想取代我？
I'm just making fun, is all.
我只是开玩笑，没别的意思
Bob was sent away cordially the next day...
第二天鲍勃就被热忱的送走了…
...with a goodbye from Jesse...
…杰西向他告了别…
...but nothing from Zee beyond what good manners demanded.
…但芝却没有礼节性的同他告别
It was 40 miles to his sister's farm from Kansas City.
从堪萨斯市到他姐姐的农场有40里地
And it was well into the afternoon by the time he arrived there.
他到那儿时已经接近傍晚了
Mrs. Martha Bolton rented the Harbison farm in 1879...
玛莎・博尔顿太太在1897年成为寡妇之后…
...just after becoming a widow.
…就出租了她的哈比森农场
And she made a good income by giving rooms and meals...
靠着出租房间和提供饮食，她收入颇丰
...to her brothers Charley, Wilbur and Bob, and to members of the James Gang...
…住户包括他的弟弟查理，威尔伯和鲍勃 还有詹姆斯一伙…
...who would appear whenever they needed seclusion.
…他们在需要躲避风头的时候就会来这里
Dick! You're gonna make her sick!
迪克！你会把她弄出毛病的！
She's gonna upchuck if you don't watch out!
你要是不小心她会吐的！
Wood Hite had been spurned by Martha in his affections...
伍德・海特追求玛莎被拒绝…
...and his attempt to switch his pursuit to her daughter...
…而他转而追求她女儿的企图…
...was being thwarted by Dick Liddil.
…也因迪克・利都而遭到挫败
Wait a second, you assured me that you were not ticklish.
等等，你得向我保证你没那么难缠
Howdy!
你好！
What's going on, now? What's going on...?
这是怎么回事？怎么回事…？
- Howdy! - Were you fibbing about that?
- 你好！ - 你是在撒谎吗？
- No. - Not at all.
- 不是 - 完全不是
You're not supposed to peek, Dick.
你不该偷看的，迪克
Well, you're just so pretty I can't help myself.
是啊，不过你这么漂亮 我真的无法把持
- You need to be warning him about that. - Howdy.
- 这事你得警告他 - 你们好
Worry about the field instead, might be able to worry about the work...
应该关心的是地里的庄稼 也应该关心关心工作…
Howdy!
你们好！
- Finally home. - I'm so glad, Bob.
- 终于到家了 - 我很高兴，鲍勃
I'm in that room too, Bob. Don't mess with my things.
我也住那个房间，鲍勃 别把我的东西弄乱了
All right, Grandpa.
好的，爷爷
"July 9th. Diligence, tact, and a keen sense of responsibility...
“7月9日 勤奋，机智，强烈的责任感…
...capacity for detail are your dominant traits. Your sense of duty's strong."
…细致入微，这些都是你的强项 你很敬业”
How long you been there?
你在这多久了？
Just now arrived. Did I miss much?
刚来，错过了很多好看的东西吗？
Not unless you never seen a man wash his dirty carcass before.
如果你从没见过一个肮脏的男人洗澡 那么是的
Boy, you got a big old pecker for being such a little squirrel.
小伙子，你个子不大，嘴巴倒挺能说
That what you come here to see, Dick?
你来这里看什么，迪克？
No.
没什么
Your brother said that Jesse kept you in Kansas City some extra days.
你哥哥说杰西在堪萨斯城多留了你几天
What was the reason?
为什么？
Well, I'm not at liberty to say exactly.
这个，我恐怕不方便细说
Let me ask you this. Did Jesse mention that me and Cummins were in cahoots?
那我这么问你吧 杰西有提到我和康明斯在一起谋事吗？
Is that so?
有这回事？
Oh, dear. I went on and said too much, have I?
哦，亲爱的，我说漏嘴了，是吧？
Well, who else is partners with you two?
那么，还有谁跟你们一伙的？
See, he'll cut our throats if he finds out. You don't know him like I do.
听着，要是被他知道，他会割断我们的喉咙 你不像我这么了解他
You do Jesse dirt, you connive behind his back...
谁要是跟着杰西干那些见不得人的事 然后又背着他密谋别的勾当…
...boy, he'll come after you with a cleaver.
…孩子，会被他带着镰刀追杀的
So, what are you two cahoots cooking up?
那你们俩在密谋什么呢？
Don't know that I should say.
不知道我该说不该说
I'm not gonna wheedle the dang news from you.
我可不会花言巧语 骗你说出你那肮脏的小秘密
How about we'll leave it a mystery...
不如我们让它成为一个谜…
...and then we won't neither one of us regret our little chat?
…这样我们都不会为这次谈话后悔？
Can you hand me that six-gun there, Bob?
能把那把转轮枪给我看看吗，鲍勃？
If you so much as mention my name to Jesse...
如果你胆敢跟杰西提起我的事…
...boy, I'll find out about it.
…孩子，我会知道的
You had better believe that.
你最好相信我
And I'll look you up.
然后我会找到你
I'll knock on your door, and I will be as mad as a hornet.
敲开你的门，暴跳如雷
I will be hot.
我会毫不留情
You be careful with that iron, Dick.
注意点手上的家伙，迪克
You know where I stand on these matters and that's all there is to it.
你知道我在这些问题上的立场 事情就这么简单
Me and you can be as friendly as pigs from now on.
我们从此以后还是亲密无间
I'm Bunny Ford, stick your hands up in the air!
我是兔崽子・福特，把手举起来！
Mister.
先生
Oh, you have some nerve.
噢，你们胆子还不小啊
We were just reading about the James boys among the Mexicans.
我们刚在看 詹姆斯小伙子们和墨西哥人的故事
What's this? This ain't Jesse.
这是谁？这不是杰西
- You don't know that. - He would've never wore no mustache.
- 你怎么知道 - 他不可能没有胡子
Never was anywheres near a cannon.
他也不可能摸过大炮
Let me see that picture.
让我看看这张
Boy, I can't even calculate what I'm looking at.
孩子，我真不知道我在看什么
- Give me that. - Ever since he was a child...
- 给我 - 他从小时候起…
...Bob's collected whatsoever he could find about the James brothers.
…就开始收集 任何和詹姆斯兄弟有关的东西
Yeah, got himself a little museum in his room.
是啊，在房间里都搞了一个小博物馆
Next time you come snooping around, you better strap on a shooting iron!
下次你再来偷看，最好随身带把枪防身！
Well, you can see how scared I am.
喔，看我多害怕
You too, Wood Hite. Cross me again, I'll put a bullet through your head!
你也是，伍德・海特 再惹我，就一枪崩了你！
Boy, you...
孩子，你…
Son, you better recollect who my cousin is...
小子，你最好想想我表哥是谁…
...because you've seemed to misremembered that Jesse loves me like the Good Book.
…你也许忘了 杰西就像珍惜圣经一样疼我
Now, you may play it like you're a dangerous person in the grocery store...
现在，你可以装成一个 杂货店里的危险人物…
...but don't misremember who you be accounting to...
…但别忘了，如果你伤害了我的感情…
...if I so much get my feelings hurt. - I don't care!
…你将面对的是谁 - 我才不管！
Do I have to yell "suwee"?
是不是要我喊，“嘿哟”
Why don't we make up, be pleasant for once?
我们为何不先和好一阵子呢？
Why don't we pass the evening like pleasant human beings?
快快乐乐的度过这个晚上，不好么？
I like your nickel suit, cowboy.
衣服不错，牛仔
You see something?
看到什么了吗？
Just a bird.
一只鸟而已
The month of October came...
十月到来了…
...and Jesse began seeing Pinkerton operatives in every floor walker...
…杰西开始发现 私家侦探装扮成售货员…
...street sweeper, and common man poking about in a store.
…扫路工和普通人在一家店里打探消息
On the morning of the 11 th, he would wake his wife...
11号的早晨，他叫醒妻子…
...with the Scripture pertaining to the Holy Family's flight into Egypt.
…就像圣经里，圣家逃往埃及一样
Overnight, the Thomas Howard clan vanished from Kansas City.
一夜间，托马斯・霍华德一家 就从堪萨斯市消失了
Shortly thereafter, four of the Blue Cut train robbers...
之后不久，蓝切地劫车案中的四个人…
...were arrested in shacks near Glendale.
…在格兰代尔附近的一间木屋里被捕
How Jesse could have known remains a mystery.
杰西是如何预先知道的，至今还是个迷
Theirs was a wandering existence.
他们居无定所
Men who choose to be outlaws...
选择了犯罪这条路…
...cannot afford to remain in one place for very long.
…就不能在一个地方呆上太久
- Well, goodness. Maybe I'll change my mind. - Let's go. Let's go. Let's go.
- 喔，天哪，也许我要改变主意了 - 快走，快走
- Martha. - Buck up, man.
- 玛莎 - 忘了吧，哥们
Wood and Dick would bicker across the entire state of Kentucky...
伍德和迪克 在跨越整个肯塔基州的途中都在斗嘴
...until they made Russellville, home of Major George Hite, Wood's father...
…一直到了罗斯威尔 伍德的父亲，也就是詹姆斯兄弟的叔叔…
...and uncle to Frank and Jesse James.
…乔治・海特上校的家
You stay away from this one.
你离她远点
She's my daddy's wife.
他是我爸的妻子
You got it?
明白了吗？
Did you cook this, ma'am?
这菜是您做的吗，太太？
I've got a nigger woman.
我有个黑人女仆
How's that?
他说什么？
Dick asked if I cooked this.
迪克问菜是不是我做的
Did you?
是你做的吗？
No.
不是
She knew what he was like when she married him.
她嫁给他的时候知道他是这样的
I guess we're the night owls, you and I.
看来我们都是夜猫子，你和我
I'm glad.
我很高兴
How come?
怎么说？
You're interesting to look at.
你看起来挺有意思
You have a real pleasant disposition.
你的性格让人感到很舒服
And I don't know, you sort of make me feel warm all over.
我也说不清楚，似乎你让我感到全身温暖
You know, I'm what they call a... An inamorato.
知道吗，别人都叫我…多情浪子
Well, I knew there had to be a name for it.
嗯，我就知道你该有个外号
You and the Hites don't get along too well...
如果伍德所说的片面之辞不假…
...if I'm to trust Wood and his version of the situation.
…你和海特一家相处的不大好啊
We hate each other like poison, if you wanna know the truth.
事实是，我们都恨透了对方
Most of the Hites wouldn't spit on me if I was on fire.
如果我身上着火了 海特家族大部分人都会袖手旁观
They say that when a woman's on fire...
人们说，如果一个女人身上着了火…
...you're supposed to roll her around on the ground and cover her with your body.
…你应该抱着她在地上打滚 并用身体罩住她
Well, you are a naughty tease.
哼，你欺负人
Isn't it about bedtime?
不该睡觉了吗？
Well, I'll just kiss those dainty nubbins.
好的，我只是想亲吻一下这双娇小的手
Good night.
晚安
Would you stop?
你有完没完？
Boy, I believe I drank too much coffee.
孩子，我想我咖啡喝多了
I gotta go visit the privy something terrible.
受不了了，我要去趟厕所
This is embarrassing.
太难为情了
Now, you go ahead and do your duty. I don't mind.
你继续你的吧，我不介意
I've sort of got stage fright with a strange man in the commode with me.
和一个陌生男人一起在厕所里 我可感到有些惊讶
I ain't strange.
为什么会陌生呢
I'm built just like the rest of them.
我和其他男人的构造没什么区别
You look awful pretty.
你看起来美极了
Do I?
是吗？
I haven't never in my life seen such well-shaped limbs.
我这辈子还从没见过这么美的大腿
Is Wood awake?
伍德还醒着么？
It's just me.
这里只有我
And I bet you thought I was a lady.
希望你还能当我是个淑女
Well, you ain't much of a housekeeper, are you?
嗯，看上去你不大会收拾啊，对吧？
You didn't just happen by.
你不是偶尔路过
Why not?
为什么呢？
Go on and take a load off your feet.
过来休息一下吧
You ought to get yourself a wife.
你该讨个老婆了
Yeah.
是啊
I suppose.
我想是的
I was gonna ask Martha. Charley's sister.
我想问问玛莎，查理的姐姐
I was gonna ask her if she could imagine it.
我想问问她有没有这个意思
But I guess Wood has plans of his own.
但估计伍德有他自己的打算
And there's always Dick Liddil getting in the way.
而且迪克・利都还总是在中间插一腿
I'll give it some thought, though.
但我还是会考虑一下
Your crops come in?
庄稼收成怎样？
No, I don't got much. Just a garden patch and a pasture.
没啥收获，只有一个小园子和一个牧场
I was sick at planting time.
播种时我正好生病了
So...
所以…
Ed, how you feeling now?
艾德，你怎么了？
Why?
为什么这么问？
You're acting queer.
你举止有点古怪
Well, you and me ain't been just real good friends lately.
是么，因为你我最近关系不是很好
That's not your fault, you understand that.
这不是你的错，你心里明白
You hear talk, though.
但你也听到传言了
Talk?
传言？
People tell you things.
别人谈论你
Why don't you give me an example?
你说来听听？
Jim Cummins come by here.
吉姆・康明斯来过这里
Jim Cummins.
吉姆・康明斯
Oh, and Jim says:
噢，吉姆说
"You know them boys that got caught in the Blue Cut deal?"
“你认识那些因为蓝切地案被捕的家伙？”
Well, Jim says he got word...
这个，吉姆说他听到谣言…
...that you're planning to kill them.
…说你准备杀了他们
Why would I do that?
我为什么要那么做？
That's just talk probably.
也许只是谣言而已
Jim Cummins. He say anything else?
吉姆・康明斯，他还说了别的什么？
Nope. No, that was it, basically.
没了，基本上，就这些
That still don't explain why you're scared.
但我还是不明白你为什么害怕
Well, I'm in the same situation, you see.
这个，因为你知道 我的处境也和他们一样
I was terrified I saw you ride up.
我看到你骑马过来的时候很害怕
- I just happened by, Ed. - Suppose you heard gossip, though.
- 我只是路过，艾德 - 但也许你听到传言了
Suppose you heard Jim Cummins come by, you might have thought...
也许你听说吉姆・康明斯来过 也许你会想…
...that we were planning to capture you or get that reward, and that ain't true.
…我们准备抓住你去领赏钱 没这回事
But you might have suspected it.
但你有可能会怀疑
Haven't heard a lick of gossip lately.
最近没听说什么闲言碎语
I got 600 dollars stashed away. I don't need no governor's reward.
我藏着六百块钱呢，我不需要政府的赏金
Well, it's the principle too.
嗯，这也是原则问题
Well...
那么…
- I'm glad I stopped by. - Oh, me too.
- 很高兴路过这里 - 噢，我也是
What do you say if we were to go for a ride?
我们一起出去骑马如何？
We can go into town. I'll buy you dinner.
我们可以去镇上，我请你吃晚饭
Then I'll be on my way.
然后我走我的
Okay.
好的
You ready to go for a ride?
有空出去骑马吗？
We going to your place?
我们这是要去你那里吗？
You seen Ed Miller lately?
你最近有看到艾德・米勒吗？
Nobody has.
没人看到
Must have gone off to California.
一定是去加州了
I'd still like to know where we're going.
我想知道我们这是要去哪儿
If you were going to see Jim Cummins, wouldn't you follow this road?
如果我们要去见吉姆・康明斯 你还打算去吗？
I guess so.
我想会的
Howdy.
你好
Oh, are you friends of my pa's?
噢，你是我爸爸的朋友吗？
We're friends of Jim Cummins.
我们是吉姆・康明斯的朋友
Well, it so happens he's been gone since August.
这样，很不巧，他八月以后就不在了
And never said where he gone to.
他也没说去哪儿了
- I'm Matt Collins. - Albert Ford.
- 我叫马特・柯林斯 - 艾伯特・福特
Very happy to meet you.
很高兴认识你
- Dick Turpin. - Pleased to make your acquaintance.
- 迪克・杜尔宾 - 很高兴认识你
I don't know where he is! Leave me alone!
我不知道他在哪里！放开我！
Shut your mouth! You shut your mouth!
闭嘴！闭嘴！
- You shut your mouth. - I don't know where he is!
- 你给我闭嘴 - 我不知道他在哪儿！
- I don't know! - Get in there.
- 我不知道！ - 给我进来
Shut up.
闭嘴
- I don't know where he is! - Shut up.
- 我不知道他在哪儿！ - 闭嘴
- I don't know!
- 我不知道！
- Jesus. - Shut up.
- 老天 - 闭嘴
Jesse, he's just a kid.
杰西，他只是个孩子
He knows where his uncle Jim is and that's gonna make him old soon enough.
他知道他的吉姆叔叔在哪里 这会让他很快变老
- Maybe he doesn't know. - He knows!
- 也许他真的不知道 - 他知道！
You need to ask and ask sometimes.
有时候就是要多问几次
Sometimes a child don't remember so much at first. But it'll come back to him.
有时候小孩子一开始并不记得 但过一阵子就会想起来
My goodness, she's about to rip off, sweetie.
老天，快能撕下来了，宝贝
Just a little more here to get her started.
再用点力就能撕出口来了
Then I think I can rip her off like a page from a book.
然后我就能像撕一页书那样把它扯下来了
Jesus, he can't even talk.
老天，他都说不了话
Where's Jim?
吉姆在哪里？
Where's Jim? Where's Jim?
吉姆在哪里？吉姆在哪里？
Where's Jim? Where's Jim? Where's Jim?
吉姆在哪里？吉姆在哪里？吉姆在哪里？
- Where's Jim? - Quit it!
- 吉姆在哪里？ - 放手！
You bastard! I don't know where he is!
你个畜生！我不知道他在哪里！
You won't believe me! You never even gave me a chance!
你就是不相信我！ 你连说话的机会都不给我！
You kept my... You kept my mouth shut!
你把我…你把我嘴巴堵上了！
I never know where Jim is or when he comes! So leave me alone.
我从来不知道 吉姆在哪里或什么时候能回来！别烦我了
Get off me, you son of a bitch!
放开我，你个狗娘养的！
I'm worn out.
我受够了
I can't. No, see...
我不能，不能…
My mind's all tangled anyway.
反正我早已心乱如麻
Little deals like this just make me feel dirty.
这种小勾当都会让我感到恶心
Are you all right, Jesse?
你没事吧，杰西？
Jesse was sick...
杰西病倒了…
...with rheums, and aches and lung congestions.
…感冒，疼痛，肺淤血
Insomnia stained his eye sockets like soot.
失眠使他眼窝严重发黑
He read auguries in the snarled intestines of chickens...
他从鸡那缠绕的肠道中…
...or the blow of cat hair released to the wind.
…或者是猫毛在风中飘散的方向中 占卜未来
And the omens promised bad luck, which moated and dungeoned him.
得到的都是凶兆，这让他感觉身陷囹圄
How come it's you that's gotta do all the chores?
为什么这些活都是你干？
Charley and Bob pay extry to Martha so that they don't have to.
查理和鲍勃多给了些钱给玛莎 所以他们就不用做
It still don't seem fair.
但还是不公平
Martha.
玛莎
Well, look what the cat dragged in.
噢，看看谁来了
You come from Kentucky?
你从肯塔基来的？
Why do you have your head in a hole, Martha?
你怎么两耳不闻窗外事，玛莎？
Wood and Dick had a shooting scrape a few months ago.
伍德和迪克几个月前有过枪战
Cover the kettle, Ida.
去看着水壶，爱达
And what did you and Dick get in a scrape about?
你和迪克为什么那样？
Well, he tampered with my daddy's wife...
我爸爸的老婆在煎猪排的时候…
...while a pork chop burned on the skillet...
…他却来和她调情…
...so I shot at him.
…所以我向他开枪
Ida! Do not stick your thumb in the cream when you skim it.
爱达！ 撇油脂的时候不要把大拇指伸进去！
His chicanery and his philandering ways...
他的狡诈和沾花惹草的作风…
...has instigated such malice.
…是我们之间怨恨的导火索
He's a yellow snake in the grass and he can't be trusted, Martha.
他就像草丛中的黄蛇一样不可靠，玛莎
Dick told me a complete other version of that affray.
但这事迪克的说法和你完全不同
Wood Hite's downstairs.
伍德・海特在楼下
You mean he's here?
你说他来这儿了？
Yeah, he come in late last night.
对，他昨晚很晚来的
Hey, simmer down!
嗨，冷静点！
Don't get into a fracas up there, you boys! I've got breakfast almost ready.
别上去惹事了，孩子们！早饭马上就好了
He's still sucking air.
他还在吸气
But I think he's a goner.
但我想他应该挂了
Maybe y'all better come wish him well on his journey.
也许你们该上来祝他黄泉路上走好
Wood?
伍德？
You were a good fellow, Wood.
你是个好伙计，伍德
Oh, I sure hope you're not in frightful pain, Wood.
哦，希望你没受太多苦，伍德
I'd get you something to drink, but I'm afraid you'd just choke on it.
我想给你点水喝，但我怕你会噎着
Little Ida's gonna miss you.
小爱达会想你的
So is the rest of the family.
家里其他人也会的
Well, one thing's settled. Can't take him into Richmond.
嗯，这事算解决了 不过不能把他带到里士满去
Why not?
为什么？
Well, one, sheriff'll put Bob in jail.
这个，一来，警察会把鲍勃抓进去
And two, Jesse'll find out his cousin Wood's been shot in our house...
二来，要是杰西发现 他的表弟被杀死在我们这里…
...and then that'll be the end of each and every one of us.
…那我们就都完了
"And in one merciless, violent thrust broke in...
“冷酷而又残暴得插了进来…
...and carried all before him, and scented and brewed...
…伴随着香水和啤酒…
...reeking with blood of my virginity...
…还有我处子之血的味道…
...up to its utmost length in my body."
…在我的身体内膨胀到了极致”
He ain't disappeared, if that's what you were hoping.
他并没有消失，让你失望了
What chapter you on?
你在读哪一章？
She's met some Algerian corsair down at Gibraltar.
她在直布罗陀遇到了一些阿尔及利亚海盗
Got herself all agitated.
这让她很兴奋
How's that leg?
腿怎样了？
Full of torment, Bob. Thanks for asking.
痛得要死，鲍勃，谢谢你的关心
Blessed are the poor in spirit...
虚心的人有福了…
...for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.
…因为天国是他们的
Blessed are them that mourn, for they shall be comforted.
哀恸的人有福了，因为他们必得安慰
Blessed are the...
…的人有福了…
Meek.
温柔
Blessed are the meek.
温柔的人有福了
- Is it him? - Yeah.
- 是他吗？ - 是的
Why is he here? Does he know about Wood, do you think?
他来这儿干嘛？ 你觉得他知道伍德的事情吗？
I don't know. All I know is he don't miss very much.
我不清楚，我只知道他不是很想念他
- What should I say about you if he asks? - Tell him I'm in K.C. With Mattie.
- 如果他问到你，我该怎么回答？ - 告诉他我和马蒂在堪萨斯城
He was buffalo hunting. He was thrilled to meet yours truly.
他在猎杀野牛 能见到你们他真的很高兴
Yeah, over there in Europe there's only two Americans they know for certain...
是啊，在欧洲，有两个美国人 人们肯定认得…
...Mark Twain and Jesse James.
…马克・吐温和杰西・詹姆斯…
- Why, it's the kid. - How's everything?
- 怎么，是这个孩子 - 一切还好吗？
- I never take off my gun belts. - Yeah?
- 我从不摘下枪 - 是吗？
Good thinking.
好主意
Well, Charley, did you hurt your leg?
噢，查理，你脚受伤了？
Yeah, I slipped... I slipped off the roof...
是啊，我滑…我从屋顶滑下去了…
...and I smacked down into a snow bank like a ton of stupidness.
…像个傻子一样摔在了雪地上
One second I'm screaming, "Whoa, Nelly!"
前一秒我还在惊叫，“噢，天哪”
Next second, poof, I'm neck-deep in snow.
后一秒我已经被埋在齐脖深的雪地里了
Well, whatever possessed you to climb a roof in December?
那么，是什么让你在大冬天爬上屋顶的？
There was a k... A kite. What am I saying? There was a cat.
有一个…风筝 我说啥来着？有一只猫
A cat. It was on the roof and I went after him.
一只猫，在屋顶上，我去追它
It was a tomcat yowling and what all, and I slipped.
是只公猫，在嗷嗷叫，我就摔了
I thought maybe your club foot was gaining on you.
我以为你畸形腿了呢
Oh, yeah.
是啊
Dick went to Kansas City to be with his wife. He was here for a bit.
迪克去堪萨斯见他老婆去了 他之前在这呆过一阵子
Hey, here's a cute story, Jess.
对了杰西，给你讲个可爱的故事吧
Bobby was what, 11 or 12...
鲍勃11还是12岁的时候
...and you were by far his most admired personage.
非常非常仰慕你
He couldn't get enough.
不停地讲你
It was "Jesse this" and "Jesse that" and "Jesse this" from sunrise to sunset.
“杰西这样”、“杰西那样” 一天到晚说不倦
Fascinating.
真有趣
No, there's more. This is cute.
还有更逗的呢
We're at supper and Bob asks, "You know what size boot Jesse wears?"
有次我们在吃饭，鲍勃问 “你们知道杰西穿几号鞋吗？”
- Charley, Jesse doesn't wanna hear this. - Shush, now, Bob, let me tell it.
- 查理，杰西不想听这个 - 鲍勃别插嘴，让我说嘛
Bob says... He says, "You know what size boot Jesse wears?"
鲍勃说，“你知道杰西穿几号鞋吗？”
He says, "Six and a half." He says, "Ain't that a big enough boot...
他说，“6寸半”，还说，“这够大吗？”
...for a man 5'8"tall?"
“他五尺八寸高呢”
I decided to josh him a little, you know, he being my kid brother and everything.
我就想逗逗他，他是我小弟弟嘛
So I said, "He doesn't have toes is why."
我就说，“因为他没有脚指头啊"
That's a really stupid story.
这故事太傻了啊
"He was dangling his feet off a culvert and a catfish nibbled his toes off."
“他有一次脚泡在水沟里， 趾头被鲶鱼啃没了”
Bob taxed himself trying to picture it.
鲍勃想破了头，就是想不明白
That'd be a good joke if it was funny.
如果你觉得这故事好笑的话， 倒是个好笑话
Isn't that a cute story, Jess?
很逗吧，杰西？
Give me some more conversations, Bob.
多给我讲讲吧，鲍勃
I got one. This one's about as crackerjack... It's the one about your...
我想到了一个更牛的，是关于你…
Let Bob tell it.
让鲍勃讲吧
All right.
好吧
I don't even know what you're talking about.
我都不知道你说什么
About how you and Jesse have so much in common.
你不是说你和杰西有很多共同点嘛
Go on, Bob.
来讲讲吧，鲍勃
Yeah, come on, Bob.
对啊，快，鲍勃
Tell us a story.
给我们讲个故事
- Nope. No. - Come on, entertain Jesse. He's here.
- 不要 - 快啦，让杰西高兴一下
Come on.
说嘛
Well, if you'll pardon my saying so, I guess...
说了你不要生气，我觉得
...it is interesting the many ways you and I overlap and whatnot.
我们俩有很多重叠的地方，挺有趣的
I mean, you begin with our daddies.
从我们的爸爸说起吧
Your daddy was a pastor at the New Hope Baptist Church...
你爸爸是个浸信会牧师
...and my daddy was a pastor at the church in Excelsior Springs.
而我爸爸是艾克塞尔西奥泉市的牧师
You're the youngest of three James boys, and I'm the youngest of five Ford boys.
你是家里三个兄弟中最小的 我家五兄弟，我最小
Between Charley and me, there's another brother, Wilbur...
查理和我中间还有一个哥哥，韦伯
...with six letters in his name.
他的名字是六个字母的
And between Frank and you, is another brother Robert, also with six letters.
你和弗兰克中间有个哥哥叫罗伯特 名字也是六个字母的
And my Christian name is Robert, of course.
恰好我的洗礼教名也是罗伯特
You have blue eyes, I have blue eyes.
你眼睛是蓝的，我也是
You're 5'8"tall, I'm 5'8" tall.
你五尺八寸高，我也是
Me, I must have had a list as long as your nightshirt when I was 12, but...
我12岁的时候列出来一长串的相似点 比你睡衣还长呢
...I seem to have lost some curiosities over the years.
但是长大后这种好奇心了就没了
Ain't he something?
他还真厉害
Did I ever tell you the story about that scalawag, George Shepherd?
我有没有给你们讲过 有个叫乔治・谢坡德的家伙
Shepherd's one of Quantrill's lieutenants.
他是考崔尔（内战时南方联盟游击队指挥官） 底下的一个官兵
He give me a story much like Bob's what bring him to mind.
我想起他是因为 他的故事和鲍勃有点像
Going on about how much we had in common, and so on...
他给我讲 我们俩有多少多少相似点
...so he could get in the gang.
就想加入我们
How could I have known he had a grudge against me?
没想到他对我心怀怨恨
he was lying to get on my good side?
没想到他为了赢得我欢心，谎话连篇
I said, "George, come on aboard. Glad to have you."
我说，"乔治，加入我们吧，很高兴你入伙”
George thought he was smart, except he wasn't.
乔治以为自己很聪明，但其实不然
One morning, George rides into camp...
有天早上，乔治进来营地
...and about 20 guns open up on him.
就有二十来支枪指着他
See, old George, he only had one eye. You gotta have two eyes, you wanna get Jesse.
乔治只有一只眼， 要阴杰西，得有两只眼
You ought not think of me like you do George Shepherd.
你不应该把我和乔治・谢坡德相提并论
You brought him to mind.
你让我想起了他
Well, it's not very flattering.
这不是什么抬举我的话
Sure is good eating, Martha.
饭做得真好吃，玛莎
Well, I'm so glad you enjoyed it.
你喜欢就好
How come George had a grudge against you?
乔治为什么会对你心怀怨恨？
I said, how come George
我问你呢，乔治为什么会对你心怀怨恨？
Well, you see, George had a nephew he wanted me to protect during the war.
乔治有个侄子 他想让我在内战时，保护他侄子
This nephew had 5000 dollars on him.
那人身上有5000美元
It just so happens he winds up killed and someone swipes that money.
结果他被杀了，钱也被抢光
And when George is in prison, someone whispers to him:
乔治蹲监狱的时候，有人偷偷告诉他
"It was Jesse James slit the boy's throat."
“是杰西・詹姆斯杀了那孩子的"
It was just mean gossip, was it?
只是些流言蜚语，是吧？
Bob's the expert. Let's put it to him.
鲍勃是这方面的专家， 我们请教他吧
Oh, dear, I made him cranky.
哦，天啊，我惹恼他了
I'm not cranky. I just been through this before is all.
我没有生气，只是以前我经历过这种事
Most people get around on making fun of me. They don't ever let up.
周围的人都嘲笑我，没完没了
Someone's getting awful fresh over there.
某人真够怕羞的
Woman, shut your face for once.
女人，闭嘴行吗
Don't want you to skip off to your room and pout...
我不想你溜回房间生闷气
...without knowing why I come by for this visit.
你还不知道我为什么过来这边
Why? So you could tell us how sorry you are...
为什么？想给我们道歉
...you had to slap our cousin Albert around?
因为你揍了我们的堂弟艾伯特一顿？
I come by...
我过来
...to ask if one of you two Fords...
是想问你们两兄弟
...would care to ride with me in a journey or two.
想不想和我一起上路
I guess we both agree it ought to be Charley.
我看我们都觉得应该选查理吧
You've been acting sort of testy.
你太急躁了点
Have you seen Wood Hite lately?
你最近有没有见过伍德・海特？
No. Not at all.
没有
I swear that stew had some squirrel meat in it.
这炖菜里肯定加了松鼠肉
- Still arguing with you, is it? - Yeah.
- 还在和他吵？ - 对
- You're Charles Ford? - Yes, ma'am.
- 你是查尔斯・福特？ - 是的，太太
You've seen me once or twice before.
我们以前见过
I got a letter from George Hite.
我有封乔治・海特寄来的信
He hasn't seen hide nor hair of him.
他找不到他儿子了
And you say you haven't seen Wood?
你说你没见过伍德？
No, l... I can't imagine where he could be.
我想不出来他能去哪
Yeah?
是吗？
You finished with your sleeping?
睡够了没？
I could use a couple more hours if it's no trouble.
如果没什么事的话，我想多睡几个小时
Yeah.
好吧
I been holding a discussion with myself over if I ought to tell you this or no.
我内心一直很挣扎，不知道该不该告诉你
My good side won out and...
但最后我善良的一面赢了
Well, I wanna make a clean breast of things.
我想把事情说清楚
Yeah, my mind's a little cobwebby is the only drawback.
可是我现在脑子还不太清楚
I could use a little... A little more sleep.
我还想再…再睡一会
You know I went to Kentucky?
你知道我去了肯德基州吧？
Yeah.
知道
I come back through Saline County and...
我回来途经萨林县
...I think to myself:
我想
"Why not stop by and see Ed Miller?"
“不如去看看艾德・米勒吧？”
So I do.
我就去看了
Well, things are not to my satisfaction.
不过结果我不太满意
Ed's got himself all worked up over something.
艾德为了某些事，惶惶终日的
I can see that he's lying like a rug.
我看得出来，他在扯谎
So I say to myself, "Enough's enough."
我就对自己说，“适可而止吧”
And I say to Ed, "Come on, Ed.
我对艾德说，“艾德”
Let's go for a ride."
“咱们出去走走吧”
You understand what I'm saying?
你明白我说什么吗？
Going for a ride is like...
出去走走就是
Going for a ride is like giving him what-for?
出去走走就是给他苦头吃的意思？
Exactly.
正是
So...
那么…
...Ed and Jesse...
艾德和杰西…
...they argue on the road.
…在路上吵起来了
Did you ever count the stars?
你有没有数过星星？
I can't ever get the same number. They keep changing on me.
我每次数的都不一样，它们不停在变
I don't even know what a star is exactly.
我连星星到底是什么都不清楚
Well, your body knows.
你的身体知道
It's your mind that forgot.
只是你的心忘记了
You go on ahead, partner. I'll catch up with you.
你先走，我会追上你的
It's okay.
没事
It's okay, sweetheart. It's okay.
没事的，亲爱的，没事
And when push came to shove...
吵到紧要关头上
...Jesse shot and killed him.
杰西一枪把艾德给毙了
Jesse did.
杰西杀了他
You got it.
你猜对了
You...
你…
So, you see, your...
你看
Your cousin, he got off easy.
你堂弟，我没拿他怎么样
I was just playing with Albert.
只是跟他玩玩而已
Yeah, I made him squeal once or twice myself.
是啊，我有时候也弄得他直嚷嚷
I'm just not as thorough as you are.
只是没你那么彻底而已
You got a tale to swap with me now?
作为交换，你有故事要告诉我吗？
I don't get your meaning.
我不明白你意思
Seems to me, if you have something to confess in exchange...
我觉得，如果你也有什么事情要坦白的话
...it'd only be right...
那你最好
...that you'd spit it out now.
现在就马上告诉我
I can't think of a single thing.
我想不出有什么事情
About Wood Hite, for example.
比如，伍德・海特？
I'm not gonna... I been saying over and over I can't figure out where he's gone.
我不会…我不都跟你说了 我不知道他去哪了
Now, I'm not gonna change my story just to have something to spit.
我不能睁眼说瞎话啊
- Why was your brother so agitated? - Which?
- 那为什么你弟弟那么不安？ - 哪个弟弟？
Bob.
鲍勃
That's just his way. He's antsy.
他一向都那样
You know?
知道吧？
You go on back to sleep now.
你继续睡觉吧
You got me agitated now, you see?
你现在倒让我不安了
Yeah, just ain't no peace when old Jesse's around.
是啊，杰西在的时候，谁都安定不得
You ought to pity my poor wife.
我老婆真可怜
Ed Miller was a good friend of mine.
艾德・米勒是我的好朋友
He introduced me to you at that one poker game.
有一次打扑克的时候 他把我介绍给你的
I'm a little angry with you, if you wanna know the God's honest truth.
你真那么想听实话的话 我就跟你说，我有点生你的气
You ought to pity me too.
你也该可怜一下我
As proof of his confederacy with the James Gang, Bob told the authorities...
为了证明和詹姆斯匪帮有联系 鲍勃告诉警方
...that Dick Liddil was sleeping over at the rented farmhouse...
迪克・利都正在一家租来的农舍
...while his ruined leg mended.
他的腿受伤了，在疗伤
And then, created a map of the Harbison property...
还画了一幅哈比森庄园的地图
...leaving out the creek where Wood Hite's remains now moldered.
只是没画上 他们埋藏伍德・海特尸体的那条小溪
Right, you boys are cornered!
你们被包围了！
Come on out peaceably and nobody'll get shot up!
乖乖地出来，就不会受伤！
Don't shoot!
别开枪
Come on out and show yourself!
快出来
Hello.
哈罗
We got him.
逮到他了
Give me that Colt, son.
克尔特手枪给我
- All right. - Andrew James Liddil...
- 好了 - 安德鲁・詹姆斯・利都
...I have a warrant here for your arrest...
我有你的逮捕令
Snowstorms would move over Missouri that Sunday, February 19th...
那个周日，2月19日 暴风雪席卷了密苏里州
...shutting down commerce for more than two days.
使得商铺超过两天无法营业
- Go, go, go. - Are the papers here?
- 走，走 - 文件在吗？
- He wanted to know if the papers are here. - I don't care what he wants.
- 他想知道，文件在不在 - 我才不在乎他要什么
Yet this wouldn't prevent Robert Ford...
但这并没有阻止罗伯特・福特
...from presenting himself to Governor Crittenden...
去参加克里廷顿州长
...at the Craig Rifles Ball on Wednesday.
周三为克莱格步枪队举行的庆功晚会 并和州长会面
I deem it a great privilege on this glorious occasion...
趁着这个难得的机会
...to recognize publicly...
我想公开表扬
...the intelligent and effective assistance...
亨利・克莱格队长那机智迅速的行动
...that Captain Henry Craig has rendered the state of Missouri and myself...
协助我和密苏里州
...in our joint quest to rid Jackson County...
在杰克森县
...of the James band.
消灭詹姆斯匪帮
The task that Captain Craig has assumed...
克莱格队长的任务
...will require fearless courage, extraordinary vigilance...
是需要无所畏惧，高度警惕
...and an unerring selection of instrumentalities.
方法适当，才能完成的
Well, I've gotten the signal from my wife that enough is enough.
我妻子暗示我，话说到这里就够了
However, before I sit...
但是，最后我还想
...I would like to ask you to join me in a toast...
希望大家和我一起
...to a great son of the state of Missouri...
向这位密苏里州的儿子
...my friend, Henry Craig. - Here, here.
- 我的朋友，亨利・克莱格祝酒 - 恭喜，恭喜
Yes.
是啊
Just let my attorney know.
告诉我的律师吧
Who is that? Who is it?
那是谁？是谁？
Get out of the way now.
走开
You know, you're more goddamn trouble than you're worth, Bob.
你惹的麻烦太多了
I was just gonna say hello.
我只是想打个招呼而已
No, you weren't gonna do that, Bob. That's not why you're down here.
不行啊，鲍勃，所以把你带下来了
You think it's your goddamn coming-out. You think you're the belle of the ball.
你以为你自己是 在晚会上华丽亮相的美女吗？
Now you get upstairs and try to keep your identity secret, you silly little bastard.
上楼去，别暴露身份了，小混蛋
The governor'll see you in good time. Take him up, boys.
到合适的时候，州长会见你的 带他上楼
Bob would later be cross-examined repeatedly...
之后，鲍勃会被不停地盘问
...about the exact nature of the deal he had made with the authorities.
解释他和警方做的交易
And he was never consistent in his recollections.
但他的回答总是自相矛盾
My wife's asleep in the other room, so let's speak as quietly as we can.
我妻子在隔壁房间睡着呢 尽量轻声说话
So you're Dick Little.
你是迪克・利秃吧？
Liddil.
利都
I beg your pardon?
什么？
I spell it with two D's.
是d的音
He's given us a full confession, governor.
他向我们全盘道出了
Newspapers haven't caught onto it yet.
报纸还没知道
And you've guaranteed him a conditional pardon...
您向他保证，会给他特赦
...and amnesty for all the robberies he's committed.
赦免他犯的所有抢劫罪
You Robert Ford?
你是罗伯特・福特？
How old are you?
多大了？
Twenty.
二十
You surrender to Sheriff Timberlake as well?
你也向汀布莱克警长投降了？
No, no, governor. That's his brother, Charley Ford, he's in the James Gang.
不是，他的哥哥查理・福特 才是詹姆斯匪帮的匪徒
But little Bob here, we got nothing on Bob.
和小鲍勃没关系
He's just acting in capacity as a...
他只是充当一个
...private detective.
秘密警探而已
Jesse James sent me a telegram last month...
杰西・詹姆斯上个月给我打了个电报
...saying he'd kill me if he had to wreck a train to do it.
说就算要拆了一整辆火车 他都要逮着我杀了我
He said once I got in his hands, he'd cut my heart out...
他说要是我落到他手上 他会把我的心割下来
...and eat it in strips like it was bacon.
像熏肉那样撕了来吃
I'll wreck his train first.
我会先拆掉他的火车
I'm sorry, Your Excellency. I was thinking about something else.
抱歉，州长大人，我在想别的事情
Jesse James is nothing more than a public outlaw...
杰西・詹姆斯只是一个匪徒
...who made his reputation by stealing whatever he wanted...
打家劫舍，臭名远扬
...killing whoever got in his way.
谁挡他的道就杀谁
You'll hear some fools say he's getting back at Republicans and Union men...
有的傻瓜说他是在报复 共和党人和联邦政府人
...for the wrongs his family suffered during the war.
因为内战时他的家人遭了不少罪
But his victims have scarcely been selected with reference to their political views.
但他甚少根据政治立场挑选受害人
I'm saying his sins will soon find him out.
我跟你们说，他的罪孽很快会遭到报应
I'm saying his cup of iniquity is full.
他造的孽也快到头了
I'm saying Jesse James is a desperate case...
杰西・詹姆斯是个极端案件
...and may require a desperate remedy.
也需要极端的制裁
Y'all got the right man for the job.
那您就找对人了
Come on. Come on, now.
快走呀
Come on, now.
快走
Have you ever considered suicide?
你有没有想过自杀？
I can't say that I have. There's always something else I wanted to do.
没有吧，总是有想做的事
Or my predicaments changed, or I saw my hardships from a different slant.
有时候事情有转机了 有时候我会换一个角度看问题
You know all what can happen. It never seemed respectable.
以后会发生什么事谁也不知道 自杀太不值得了
I'll tell you one thing that's for certain.
告诉你吧，有一件事是肯定的
You won't mind dying once you've peeked over the other side.
你窥见过死后世界之后 就不介意死掉了
You'll no more wanna go back to your body than...
你不会再想回到你的身体里
...you'd wanna spoon up your own puke.
就好像你不会想把自己的呕吐物 给吃回去一样
Hey, since we're looking to rob banks...
嘿，我们计划抢银行的话
...I was wondering if we could add another fella to the gang...
不如再加一个人
...and sort of see if we couldn't come out of our next job alive.
下次干活的时候好保着命呀
Bob wanted to know could he ride with us next time we took on a savings bank or...
鲍勃想知道，他下次能不能和我们 一起去打劫银行或者…
A savings bank or a...
打劫银行或者…
A railroad.
火车
Bob isn't much more than a boy to most appearances.
鲍勃看起来虽然挺小的
But there's about two tons of sand in him.
但他资质还是挺好的
And he'll stand with a shooter when that's what's called for.
必要时候，他会使枪
And he's smart too. He's about as intricate as they come.
他挺机灵的，心思挺细的
You forget I already met the kid.
我见过这孩子，你忘了？
Hell, he surely thinks highly of you.
他很仰慕你
All of America thinks highly of me.
所有美国人都仰慕我
Still, not like you got two million names to snatch out of a sock...
但是，要找第三个人作帮手
...whenever you need a third man.
也不是说随手拈来的吧？
I can see you trying to wear me down on this.
你在努力说服我
That's my main intention.
我就是这个意思
Robberies would be conceived but never carried out...
他们密谋 在内布拉斯加，科罗拉多和密苏里州
...in Nebraska, Colorado and Missouri.
进行抢劫，但都没有开始行动
During this time...
这时
...Henry Craig enjoined Robert Ford to return to Elias' Grocery Store in Richmond...
亨利・克雷格指示罗伯特・福特 回到伊莱亚在里士满的杂货店
...and await instructions from Sheriff James Timberlake.
并在那里等候 詹姆斯・汀伯莱克警长的指示
All right, three cans...
好，三罐…
...peaches. Two cans...
桃子，两罐
Two cans sifted peas.
两罐豌豆
One bottle...
一瓶
...Mary's Morning Tonic, and a half...
玛丽牌精华露，半…
Half a sack of flour.
半袋面粉
I'll be right with you.
马上回来
I haven't seen any sign of him.
我没见过他的任何踪迹
Well, do you know where he's living?
你知道他住在哪里吗？
No.
不知道
No?
不知道？
Well, I can't guess how he does it...
我不知道他是怎么做到…
...but he is always knowledgeable about what's going on.
总是对一切了如指掌的
He's gonna know I've been here with you. You ought to take that for granted.
他会知道我在这里见你 你该做好这个心理准备
And he will kill you if he gets the chance.
一有机会他就会把你杀掉
Are you willing to risk that?
你愿意冒这个险吗？
Yes, I am.
愿意
I've been a nobody all my life.
我这辈子都那么不起眼
I was the baby.
永远当我是个小孩
I was the one they made promises to that they never kept.
答应我的事情也没实现过
And ever since I can remember it, Jesse James has been as big as a tree.
我记忆中 杰西・詹姆斯永远那么高大显赫
I'm prepared for this, Jim...
我准备好了，吉姆
...and I'm gonna accomplish it.
我会完成任务的
I know I won't get but this one opportunity...
我知道这是我唯一的机会
...and you can bet your life I'm not gonna spoil it.
我保证不会把这事毁了的
Well...
那么…
...wait for your chance.
等待合适的时机
Don't let yourself be found alone with him, and do not...
别和他独处，还有千万…
...let him get behind you.
不要让他到你身后
You been chosen.
你被选中了
Well, what do you mean?
什么意思？
Well, your brother said that you might wanna join us.
你哥哥说你想加入我们
But maybe you like this grocery store more than you said you did.
不过，你对这杂货店的感情 也许比嘴上说的更深
- So you missed me? - Oh, yeah.
- 想我了？ - 对啊
I been crying myself to sleep every night.
每晚想你想到哭
Don't let him see us so much as wink.
别让他看到我们俩
He's suspicious as a damn coyote, and he don't trust you one iota.
他现在多疑得跟个野狼似的，谁也不信
- Well, I guess that makes... - Hey.
- 那我想… - 嘿
He already put away Ed Miller. He said so like it was something piddly he'd done.
他已经干掉艾德・米勒了 还说得轻描淡写的
If we're ever alone for more than a minute, I'd like a chance to talk to you further.
如果我们俩能单独待多过一分钟 我很想再跟你谈谈
They gave me ten days.
他们给我十天时间
For what?
干吗？
For arresting him.
逮捕他
You and me, huh?
你和我?
It's gonna happen one way or another, Charley. It's gonna happen.
不是他动手就是我们动手 这事躲不过的
So it might as well be us who get rich on it.
干嘛不趁这个机会捞点钱
- Bob, he's our friend. - He murdered Ed Miller.
- 鲍勃，他是我们的朋友 - 他杀了艾德・米勒
And he's gonna murder Liddil and Cummins if the chance ever comes.
一有机会，他就会去杀利都和康明斯
It seems to me Jesse's riding from man to man, saying goodbye to the gang.
照我看来，杰西正一个个地 把帮里的兄弟做掉
So your friendship could put you under the pansies.
你的友情会害死你的
I'll grind it fine in my mind, Bob. I can't go any further than that right now.
我会认真考虑的，鲍勃 我现在只能到这一步了
You'll come around.
你会想通的
You think it's all made up, don't you?
你认为这都是编造的，是吗？
You think it's all yarns and newspaper stories.
他的故事只是报纸编的
He's just a human being.
他也不过是个人
From now on, you two won't go anywhere without me.
从今以后，你们俩不许离开我行动
From now on, you'll ask for my permission! From now on, you'll ask to be excused!
从今以后，你们的行动要得到我批准！ 要向我请示！
Charley, take them horses around the barn. Bob, you go on inside.
查理，把马带到马棚里 鲍勃，进屋去吧
- Hello, Mary. - Hi.
- 你好，玛丽 - 嗨
Look at this rotten parsnip I found in the compost heap.
看我在堆肥里找到的萝卜(欧洲萝卜）
You never mentioned Bob would be here.
你没提过鲍勃会来
Maybe he was saving it as a pleasant surprise.
可能他想留作惊喜呢
Got two cousins for company now.
现在来了两位堂兄弟做伴了
How it's gonna be is...
这么着…
...we'll leave next Monday afternoon and ride down to Platte City.
我们下周一下午离开，到普拉特市
How far is that from Kansas City?
离堪萨斯市多远？
Platte City's 30 miles south.
往南三十英里
You and me and Charley'll sleep in the woods overnight...
你，我和查理晚上在森林里睡一夜
...and we'll strike the Wells Bank sometime before the court recesses.
我们会在关门之前一段时间 进攻富国银行
What time will that be exactly?
具体是几点？
Well, you don't need to know that.
这你没必要知道
You know, I'm real comfortable with your brother.
我和你哥哥一起的时候很惬意
Hell, he's ugly as sin, he smells like a skunk...
虽然他长得难看，身上也臭
...and he's so ignorant he couldn't drive nails in the snow...
还无知得要命
...but he's sort of easy to be around.
但他很好相处
I can't say the same for you, Bob.
你就不一样了，鲍勃
Well, I'm sorry to hear you say that.
你这么说让我很难过
You know how it is when you're with your girlfriend and the moon's out...
你知道那种情况吧 你和你爱人在月色之下
...and you know she wants to be kissed, even though she never said so?
虽然她从没开口说 但你知道她等着你亲她
Yeah.
恩
Well, you're giving me signs that grieve my soul...
你的种种迹象，让我很难过
...and make me wonder...
让我觉得…
...maybe your mind's been changed about me.
可能你对我的看法已经变了
Well, what do you want me to do? Swear my good faith on the Bible?
你要我怎么办？向天发誓？
You two having a spat?
你俩在吵架？
I was getting ready to be angry.
我正准备发火呢
Sit over here closer, kid.
坐过来点，孩子
Come on.
过来过来
Charley, you'll stay with the animals.
查理，到时你看着马
Me and the kid...
我和这孩子
...will walk into that bank just before noon.
会在中午之前走进那银行
Bob will move that cashier...
鲍勃会让那出纳员
...away from the shotgun that's under the counter...
没法拿到柜台底下藏着的枪
...and I'll creep up behind that cashier...
然后我就溜到那出纳员后头
...and I'll cock his head back like so.
这样把他的头朝后扳
And I'll say:
我会说
"How come an off-scouring like you is still sucking air...
“象你这样的废柴怎么还活着
...when so many of mine are in coffins?" I'll say:
而我那么多手下就已经送命了呢？”
"How did you get to reach 20 without leaking out all over your clothes?"
“你怎么还能活到20岁？”
And if I don't like his attitude, I will slit that phildoodle so deep...
如果我不喜欢他的态度 我会狠狠地割掉那小子的喉咙
...he will flop on the floor like a fish.
让他像条脱水的鱼一样乱跳
My God, what just happened?
天啊，发生什么了？
Boy, I could hear your gears grinding...
鲍勃，我能听到你的小脑袋发动了
...hear your little motor wondering, "My gosh, what's next?
听到你在问自己 “天啊，下次他会干出什么事？”
What's happening to me?"
“我会怎么样？”
You were precious to behold, Bob.
看你这样子，鲍勃
You were white as spit in a cotton field.
脸白得跟墙一样
You got him. You got him.
你吓到他了
You wanna know how that feels? Unpleasant. I honestly can't recommend it.
你想知道这是什么感觉吗？不舒服 我真的不推荐你这么做
The old Charley looked stricken!
查理看来也被吓倒了
I was. I was.
是啊，是啊
"This is plumb unexpected," old Charley was thinking. "That done ruined my day."
“太恐怖了”，查理想道 “把我一天的心情都毁了”
Hell. Hell.
天呀
Jesse slept with Bob in the children's room that night.
那晚，杰西和鲍勃睡在孩子们的房间
And Bob remained awake.
鲍勃一直醒着
He could see that there was a gun on the nightstand.
他能看到床头柜上有一把枪
He could imagine its cold nickel inside his grip...
他能想象自己手里握着冰冷的枪
...its two-pound weight reached out and aimed.
举起这两磅的重量，瞄准
I need to go to the privy.
我要上厕所
You think you do, but you don't.
你以为你要上，但其实你不用上
You wait for grace, now.
等祷告之后再吃
- Thank you, Mama. - Thank you, Zee. God, that looks good.
- 谢谢，妈妈 - 谢谢，芝，看来很好吃哦
- Thank you, Zee. - You're welcome.
- 谢谢，芝 - 不客气
Well, is this fit to eat or will it just do?
这适合吃还是凑合？
Woman's cooking's always been a scandal.
她做饭可是臭名远播
Cut her meat and the whole table moves.
她做的肉，切起来整张桌子都得晃
You want a biscuit? You gonna have a biscuit?
想吃饼干吗？想要吗？
Here's some butter. Come on. Come on.
给你黄油，来
Oh, shoot.
哦，妈的
And so it went, Jesse was increasingly cavalier...
杰西变得越来越平易近人
...merry, moody, fey...
和蔼，情绪化，沉郁
...unpredictable.
不可预测
He camouflaged his depressions and derangements...
他把抑郁和狂乱隐藏起来
...with masquerades of extreme cordiality, courtesy...
用高度的诚恳和风度来掩饰
...and goodwill towards others.
假装对人好心好意
But even as he jested, or tickled his boy in the ribs...
但即使他开玩笑的时候 或者给他儿子呵痒的时候
...Jesse would look over at Bob with melancholy eyes...
杰西都会用忧郁的眼神看着鲍勃
...as if the two were meshed in an intimate communication.
两人仿佛在进行亲密深邃的交流
Bob was certain that the man had unriddled him...
鲍勃坚信杰西看穿了他
...had seen through his reasons for coming along...
看穿了他为什么跟来
...that Jesse could forecast each of Bob's possible moves and inclinations...
坚信杰西能预测鲍勃任何的行动和企图
...and was only acting the innocent...
杰西只是在扮无辜
...in order to lull Bob into stupid tranquility and miscalculation.
好让鲍勃放松警惕
How long you been studying me?
你盯着我看多久了？
You're gonna break a lot of hearts.
你会让很多人伤心的
How do you mean?
什么意思？
It's a present.
是份礼物
It's heavy.
很沉
Well, you gonna look inside?
打开看看？
It's April Fools' Day, you know.
今天是愚人节
It ain't no joke.
这可不是个玩笑
Oh, such extravagance.
太华丽了
Don't that nickel just shine, though?
闪亮亮的，是吧？
It's more than I could hope for.
我做梦都没想过
I figured that granddaddy Colt may blow into fragments...
你那老破枪，说不定下次开枪的时候
...next time you try to squeeze the trigger.
就得崩成一块一块的了
Well, you might have something there.
你也许说的对
Tom, supper's ready.
汤姆，饭好了
I'll be right there, sweetheart.
马上来，亲爱的
I might be too excited to eat.
我太兴奋了，都吃不下饭了
You know what John Newman Edwards once wrote about me?
你知道约翰・纽曼・爱德华兹 曾经怎么写我吗？
He said I didn't trust two men in 10,000...
他说，给我一万个人 我只能找出两个能信任的人
...and even them I was cautious around.
就算和这俩人一起，我还是很警惕
Government's sort of run me ragged.
政府长年追捕，让我疲惫不堪
I'm going the long way around the barn to say that...
我绕着圈子说话呢
...I been feeling cornered and just plain ornery as of late...
我是被追急了，最近有时故意刁难人
...and I'd be pleased if you'd accept that gun as my way of apologizing.
如果你能接受这把枪，接受我的歉意 我会很高兴的
Heaven knows I'd be ornerier if I were in your position.
如果我是你，我大概会更加刁难人
No. No, I haven't been acting correctly.
不，不，我的行为是不对的
Seems I hardly recognize myself when I'm greased.
我有时候都认不出自己了
I go on journeys out of my body...
我有时候灵魂出窍
...and look at my red hands and my mean face...
看到自己这染血的手和凶恶的脸
...and I wonder about that man that's gone so wrong.
看着这个做了那么多错事的人
I've been becoming a problem to myself.
我对自己来说，都已经成了一个麻烦
Well...
唉
- I better wash my hands if supper's on. - Yeah, go ahead.
- 该吃饭了，我去洗手 - 恩，去吧
The day before he died was Palm Sunday.
他死前一天是主进圣城节
And Mr. And Mrs. Thomas Howard, their two children...
汤玛斯・霍华德先生和他的夫人， 还有他们的两个孩子
...and their cousin Charles Johnson...
还有他们的表亲查尔斯・约翰森
...strolled to the Second Presbyterian Church to attend the 10:00 service.
到第二长老会教堂参加10点的礼拜
Bob remained at the cottage...
鲍勃留在了屋里
...and slyly migrated from room to room.
偷偷地从一个房间，走到另一个房间
He walked into the master bedroom...
他走进主人房
...and inventoried the clothes on the hangers and hooks.
把里面的衣服翻了一遍
He sipped from the water glass on the vanity.
拿起化妆台上的一杯水，喝了一口
He smelled the talcum and lilacs on Jesse's pillowcase.
闻了闻杰西枕套上的滑石粉和丁香花
His fingers skittered over his ribs...
他的手指滑过自己的肋骨
...to construe the scars where Jesse was twice shot.
想象上面像杰西那样，有两次中枪的伤疤
He manufactured a middle finger that was missing the top two knuckles.
他把中指弄成上两个关节没了那样
He imagined himself at 34.
想象自己34岁
He imagined himself in a coffin.
想象自己躺在了棺材里
He considered possibilities...
他想到各种各样
...and everything wonderful that could come true.
即将成真的好事情
He's not gonna kill us.
他不会杀我们的
Yeah, he is.
他会的
Well, I'll stay awake so he can't.
我会一直醒着，他就没法下手了
You're imagining things.
你在瞎想
Ain't gonna be no Platte City.
不会去什么普拉特市
That's Jesse fooling with us.
杰西只是在耍我们
Go to sleep, Charley.
睡吧，查理
Morning.
早
Charley.
查理
Bob, how much did you want to eat?
鲍勃，你要吃多少？
I'm feeling sort of peculiar.
我感觉有点怪怪的
Why is it you're looking so interested?
为什么那么感兴趣地看着我们？
You think it's intelligent to go out like that...
你以为这样出去晃很聪明？
...so all creation can see your guns?
让大家都看见你的枪？
Hi.
嗨
Come on, let's go see what your mama's doing.
来，看你妈妈在干吗
Timmy, get that door, would you?
提米，开门
- Well, you lost your shoe, sweetheart. - Yeah, I did.
- 你弄丢了一只鞋是吗，亲爱的 - 是啊
That's gonna be a problem. They don't sell those one at a time.
那可麻烦了，商店也不单只卖呀
We lost a shoe, Mama.
我们丢了一只鞋，妈妈
Will you put that up for Daddy, would you?
帮爸爸穿上，好吗？
- What you doing, you lose a shoe? - Yeah.
- 你在干吗，丢了一只鞋？ - 恩
It's only meant to go on top, to complement.
只会往上，作为补充
Yeah, I know. Sometimes, l...
我知道，有时候，我
Bob, everything's getting cold!
鲍勃，菜要凉了
- Where's Mary? - She's outside, darling.
- 玛丽在哪里？ - 在外面，亲爱的
Mary?
玛丽？
What do you think goes on in that noggin of his?
你说他那小脑瓜里都在想什么？
Nothing.
没什么
I was talking about his mind, not yours.
我说的是他，不是你
Oh, yeah.
哦，是啊
Oh, I get it.
哈，我明白
Well, hello now.
啊哈
"The arrest and confession of Dick Liddil."
“迪克・利都被逮捕，并已认罪”
You don't say so.
不是吧
That's very strange.
真怪了
Says here Dick surrendered three weeks ago.
上面说迪克三星期前就投降了
You must have been right in the neighborhood.
那时候你应该在那附近吧
Well, apparently, they kept it a secret.
很明显，他们是秘密行动
If I get to Kansas City soon, I'll ask somebody about it.
如果我短期内去堪萨斯市，会找人问问
You two ready?
你俩准备好了吗
I will be, by noon.
马上就好
There is a ship She sails the sea
她要上船，航行出海
She's loaded deep As deep can be
她装了很多很多东西
But not as deep As the love I'm in
但不及我对她的爱多
I know not if I sink or swim
我不知道我是浮是沉
The water is wide
海水广阔
I can't cross o'er And neither have I wings to fly
我游不过，也没法翱翔而过
Give me a boat That can carry two
给我一只能载两个人的小船
Both shall row My love and I
一起划船，我和我的爱人
For love is gentle And love is kind
柔情款款
Sweetest flower When first it's new
如初开花蕾，芬芳扑鼻
But love grows old And waxes cold
但热情一旦冷却
And fades away Like the morning dew
就像晨露一样枯萎
There is a ship She sails the sea
她要上船，航行出海
I guess I'll take my guns off...
我该把枪拿下来
...for fear the neighbors might spy them.
别让邻居看到
Don't that picture look dusty?
这画怎么那么多灰？
What have...? What have you done?
你…你做了什么？
Jesse.
杰西
Jesse?
杰西？
Jesse!
杰西！
No!
不!
No. Jess...
别，杰西
Come back. Oh, come back.
回来，回来
Oh, Jesse! No!
杰西，不要！
Oh, Bob. Have you done this?!
鲍勃，是你干的吗？
I swear to God I didn't.
我向上帝发誓，我没有
It was an accident, Zee.
是场意外，芝
Come on. Pistol went off accidentally.
枪走火了
Put my name.
[州长：我杀了杰西・詹姆斯] 写上我的名字
Why, what'd you do? I shot him.
[州长：我杀了杰西・詹姆斯。罗伯特・福特] 你做什么了？我杀了他
You might wanna keep that.
你大概会想留着它
Thank you all very much.
谢谢
The resulting prints sold for 2 dollars apiece...
照片以每张２美元的价钱卖出
...and were the models for the lithographed covers on a number of magazines.
好些杂志拿来做了封面
Soon a thousand strangers were making spellbound pilgrimages to the cottage...
成千的陌生人像着了魔一样 来到这房子来朝圣
...or were venerating the iced remains in Seidenfaden's cooling room.
到森丹法邓的冷藏室去瞻仰
The man who offered 30,000 dollars for the body of President Garfield's assassin...
有个人，曾经出价３万美元，想买下 刺杀加菲尔德・詹姆士总统那杀手的尸体
...sent a telegram to City Marshal Enos Craig offering 50,000...
他给该市警长克雷格打了个电报，出价５万
...for the body of Jesse Woodson James...
想买下杰西・詹姆斯的遗体
...so that he could go around the country with it...
准备全国展览
...or at least sell it to P.T. Barnum for his Greatest Show on Earth.
或者至少卖给P・T・巴纳姆，在其表演里展出 （美国著名游艺节目演出的经理人）
Another photograph was taken of the renowned American bandit...
另外一张照片，拍的是这位美国著名大盗
...nestled in his bed of ice.
躺在冰床上
And it was this shot that was most available in sundries and apothecaries...
这张照片在小店和药房等地方都大卖
...to be viewed in a stereoscope alongside the sphinx...
大家透过立体透镜来看这照片 就像看狮身人面像
...the Taj Mahal, and the catacombs of Rome.
泰姬陵和罗马的地下墓室 这些名胜古迹的照片一样
Hello, here!
看啊
"The arrest and confession of Dick Liddil."
“迪克・利都被逮捕，并已认罪”
Young man, I thought you told me you didn't know Dick had surrendered.
年轻人，你跟我说过 不知道迪克投降了是吧？
You mean he did? I didn't know.
真的吗？我不知道
But I knew I had not fooled him.
但我知道我骗不了他
And he knew, as well as I, in that moment that I intended to bring him to justice.
他和我一样心知肚明，那一刻我准备 把他绳之于法
But he would not kill me in the presence of his wife and children.
但他不会当着他老婆孩子的面杀我
And so he was smiling to throw me off-guard.
所以他笑了，好让我放松警惕
Well, it's all right, anyway, Bob.
哦，对阿，鲍勃
It was widely felt that Bob possessed some acting talent...
大家都认为，鲍勃相当具有戏剧天赋
...and Charley, not a jot.
而查理则一点天分都没有
That picture's awful dusty.
这画怎么那么多灰呀
Charley was only expected not to slouch or mutter...
大家希望查理不要那么垂头丧气，喃喃自语
...and to transport his sicknesses to the alley before letting them go.
不要把这种心情传给观众
And that's...
就这样
...how I killed Jesse James.
我杀了杰西・詹姆斯
By October of 1883, Bob Ford could be identified correctly...
到了1883年3月，认得鲍勃・福特的人
...by more citizens than could the president of the United States.
已经比认得美国总统的人多了
He was as renowned at 20 as Jesse was after 14 years of grand larceny.
年仅20岁，他已经非常出名，可以媲美 杰西犯了14年偷窃罪所累积出来的名气
You won't get your hooks into me.
你不会勾引到我的
That's right. That's right. Sit next to your boyfriend. Jezebel.
对了，这就对了，坐到你男朋友边上，吉贝尔
Charley was increasingly superstitious...
查理变得越发的迷信
...increasingly subject to the advice of soothsayers...
越发相信占卜者的建议
...who promised to cure his miseries with pipe smoke and poultices.
占卜者声称能用烟斗和糊药治愈他的悲伤
You been spending too much time with Gypsies, Charley.
你见吉普赛人见得太多了，查理
Shit.
靠
The picture's awful dusty.
这照片怎么那么多灰
Something began to change in Charley's stage portrayal of Jesse.
查理对杰西的演绎方式发生了变化
His gait seemed more practiced.
他的步态显得更娴熟
His voice was spookily similar to the man's.
声音越发和那人相似，让人毛骨悚然
His newly suggested dialogue was analogous...
他新加入了一些对话
...to a script Jesse might have originated.
仿佛出自杰西的创造
He began to look at his younger brother with spite...
他开始用蔑视的眼神注视他的弟弟
...as if he suspected that in some future performance...
仿佛他疑心，在以后的演出里
...he might present himself to a live cartridge in Robert Ford's gun.
他将面对罗伯特・福特的真枪实弹
Murderer!
杀人犯！
Cur!
杂种！
Coward!
懦夫！
You wanna investigate my courage? Do you?
你想看我有多大的胆子是吗？
Find out! Find out!
来啊！来啊！
Nobody.
没人来
Coward!
懦夫！
By his own approximation, Bob assassinated Jesse James over 800 times.
据他自己估计 鲍勃谋杀了杰西・詹姆斯800多次
He suspected no one in history had ever so often or so publicly...
他猜，历史上没有任何人 曾这样频繁，或如此公开地
...recapitulated an act of betrayal.
重演一次背叛的行为
Bob always challenged the allegations of cowardice...
鲍勃经常挑战对于懦夫的定义
...but Charley seemed to agree with them.
但查理似乎认同这些定义
He spoke of Mrs. Zee James as certain priests might the Madonna...
他提起芝・詹姆斯太太的时候 把她说得像圣母一样
...and composed long soul-describing letters to her...
还给她写了许多发自肺腑的长信
...begging her forgiveness...
请求她的原谅
...none of which he mailed.
但这些信从未寄出过
Charley Ford became all that his countrymen wanted an assassin of Jesse James to be.
大家觉得，暗杀了杰西・詹姆斯的人 下场就该和查理・福特一样
Jesse James was a man Who killed many men
杰西・詹姆斯杀了很多人
He robbed the Glendale train
他抢了格伦代尔火车
And he stole from the rich And he gave to the poor
他劫富济贫
He had a hand And a heart and a brain
他身手敏捷，头脑机灵
Well, Jesse had a wife To mourn for his life
杰西有个妻子，她会为他哀悼
Three children They were brave
还有三个勇敢的儿女
But that dirty little coward Who shot Mr. Howard
但那个肮脏的懦夫，射杀了霍华德先生
Has laid Jesse James in his grave
让杰西・詹姆斯进了棺材
It was Robert Ford That dirty little coward
罗伯特・福特，这肮脏的小懦夫
I wonder how does he feel
我想知道他的感受
For he ate at Jesse's bread And he slept in Jesse's bed
他吃杰西的饭，睡杰西的床
And he laid poor Jesse in his grave
却让可怜的杰西进了棺材
Well, Jesse had a wife To mourn for his life
杰西有个妻子，她会为他哀悼
Three children They were brave
还有三个勇敢的儿女
But that dirty little coward Who shot Mr. Howard
但那个肮脏的懦夫，射杀了霍华德先生
Has laid poor Jesse in his grave
让可怜的杰西进了棺材
I'm Robert Ford.
我就是罗伯特・福特
It was two children, not three.
是两个孩子，不是三个
Hey.
嘿
You get yourself home, son, okay?
回家去，好吗
Come on. Get out of here. Get out of my place.
出去，滚出我的地方
He thought, at his angriest...
他生气极了的时候
...about visiting the kin of Jesse's slaughtered victims:
会想去见杰西杀害的人的家属
Mrs. William Westfall in Plattsburg...
普拉茨堡的威廉太太
...the Wymore family in Clay County...
克莱县的崴墨一家
...perhaps even Mrs. Joseph Heywood in Northfield, Minnesota.
甚至是马萨诸塞州北田的 约瑟夫・黑伍德的遗孀
He would go to their homes and give his name as Robert Ford...
他想到这些人的家里 告诉他们他叫罗伯特・詹姆斯
...the man who killed Jesse James.
告诉他们他杀了杰西・詹姆斯
He imagined they would be grateful to him.
他想象他们会对他充满感激之情
It was only with Dorothy Evans that Bob spoke revealingly or plainly...
他只对多莱西・伊凡思坦白道出了真相
...and it was with her that he spoke of things he didn't know he knew.
告诉她一些他以前都不知道自己知道的事情
He told her that he had no real memory of the shooting and its aftermath.
他告诉她，他对射杀和后事都没有真实的记忆
He could remember lifting the gun that Jesse had given him...
他只记得，举起了那把杰西给他的枪
...and then it was Good Friday and he was reading about the funeral proceedings...
然后就到耶稣受难日了，他看到了葬礼安排
...as if they'd happened a long time ago.
仿佛事情已经过去了很久
Why did you kill him?
你为什么杀了他？
Well, he was gonna kill me.
他要杀我
So you were scared and that's the only reason?
那唯一的原因就是你害怕了？
Yeah.
对
And the reward money.
还有赏金
Do you want me to change the subject?
你想我换个话题吗？
You know what I expected?
你知道我曾经期待什么吗？
Applause.
掌声
I was only 20 years old then. I couldn't see how it would look to people.
我那时候才20岁，我不知道别人会怎么看
I was surprised by what happened.
事情竟变成这样，我很吃惊
They didn't applaud.
他们没有鼓掌
He was ashamed of his boasting...
他为自己的吹嘘
...his pretensions of courage and ruthlessness.
自己假装的勇敢无畏而感到羞耻
He was sorry about his cold-bloodedness, his dispassion...
他为自己的冷血无情
...his inability to express what he now believed was the case:
为自己无法表达自己真实的感情而充满愧疚
That he truly regretted killing Jesse...
他很后悔杀了杰西
...that he missed the man as much as anybody...
他非常想念他
...and wished his murder hadn't been necessary.
他希望，他不是非要杀了杰西来保命
Even as he circulated his saloon...
即使当他在自己的酒吧里穿行
...he knew that the smiles disappeared when he passed by.
他也知道他走过之后，这些人的笑容就会消失
He received so many menacing letters...
他收到很多很多恶意信件
...that he could read them without any reaction except curiosity.
到最后他读的时候除了好奇，就没有别的反应了
He kept to his apartment all day, flipping over playing cards...
他整天呆在屋里，翻着扑克牌
...looking at his destiny in every king and jack.
在每张K和J牌里注视自己的命运
Edward O'Kelly came up from Bachelor at 1 p.m. On the 8th.
8号下午1点，爱德华・奥凯利来了
He had no grand scheme, no strategy...
他没有什么大计，没有策略
...no agreement with higher authorities...
没有和警方订任何协议
...nothing beyond a vague longing for glory...
心里只是暗暗期待着荣誉
...and a generalized wish for revenge against Robert Ford.
和向罗伯特・福特报复的心情
- How'd it go last night? - Not so bad.
- 昨晚怎样？ - 不坏
The other one.
另一支
Edward O'Kelly would be ordered to serve a life sentence...
爱德华・奥凯利将因二级谋杀
...in the Colorado Penitentiary for second-degree murder.
在科罗拉多惩戒所被判终身监禁
Over 7000 signatures would eventually be gathered...
最终，超过7000人签名
...on a petition asking for O'Kelly's release...
请求释放奥凯利
...and in 1902, Governor James B. Orman would pardon the man.
1902年，州长詹姆斯・B・奥曼将其释放
You shouldn't be wearing that stickpin again there, Bob. Opals are unlucky.
你不应该戴那个领带夹的，蛋白石不吉祥
My luck's not very good as it is. I don't think an opal's gonna change that much.
我运气本身也不好 蛋白石可能还能给我转运呢
I hear you.
我听到了
There would be no eulogies for Bob...
没有人会给鲍勃念颂词
...no photographs of his body would be sold in sundries stores...
杂货店也不会卖他遗体的照片
...no people would crowd the streets in the rain to see his funeral cortege...
没有人会在雨天涌到街上去看他的葬礼行列
...no biographies would be written about him...
没人会给他写传记
...no children named after him.
没有人会给孩子起他的名字
No one would ever pay 25 cents to stand in the rooms he grew up in.
没有人会付25美分去看他长大的那个屋子
Hello, Bob.
你好啊，鲍勃
The shotgun would ignite, and Ella Mae would scream...
枪声响起，艾拉・梅会尖叫
...but Robert Ford would only lay on the floor and look at the ceiling...
但罗伯特・福特只会躺在地板上 盯着天花板
...the light going out of his eyes...
他的眼睛逐渐失去光彩
...before he could find the right words.
他没想到该说什么话